ALEXSANDER RAMOS DA SILVA

RAMOSDASILVA.ALEXSANDER@GMAIL.COM +55 31 99454 1790

R. Agostinho Brusamolin 333 80312-090

Detail oriented Developer with 4+ years of experience in the oil production industry seeking position with IT Team. Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills, being always interested in learning and developing using the latest and most efficient technologies. Certified SAP ABAP developer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ExxonMobil, Developer Analyst, Curitiba, Brazil

July 2020-Present

- Working in an agile global team. Multicultural and multi time zone.
- Experience developing and maintaning multiple applications. Apps on Azure Cloud and On-Premise infrastructure.
- Configured multiple integrations between On-Primises and Cloud environemnt.
- Migrated on-premise apps to the Cloud.

GTCON, Full Stack Developer, Belo Oriente, Brazil

May 2018-July 2020

- Solved a showstopper issue that was reducing the company's effectiveness while calculating the optimum timing to extract the pulp from the wood.
- Experience writing Business web/mobile applications in the Cloud (Azure). The integration with Azure AD provided secure SSO for our users. Also, the Cloud made a practical and safe way to publish our products without the need of exposing our in-house servers.
- Introduced my teammates to containers (Docker) and migrated some applications to the Cloud using this technology, which allowed CI/CD, easy management and high availability to our applications.
- Wrote Reports/Interfaces in SAP ABAP handling both Functional and Technical Incidents and Change Requests for the client CENIBRA.
- Experience working on an Agile team (SCRUM).

EDUCATION

CEFET-MG, Timóteo, Brazil

2014-2018

- Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering. GPA: 3.3/4.
- Created campus first environment for robot soccer competition.
- Two scientific researches involving computer vision, path planning, wifi communication and electronics.

PUC Minas, Distance learning, Brazil

2019-2021

Graduate degree student in Distributed Software Architecture.

SKILLS

Languages

- Portuguese (Native)
- English (Full professional proficiency)

Technologies

- Java, C/C++, C#, Python, SAP ABAP, SAPUI5, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, MySQL, Flutter,
- MongoDB, jQuery, Node.js, Angular 2+, REST, SOAP, Express.js, AutoLISP, Git, Clojure, Linux,
- PowerShell, Docker, MuleSoft, OutSystems

Home Address

Curitiba, MG, Brazil